<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artworks on Tillmann Ohm</title>
    <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artworks on Tillmann Ohm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections of HAL and Samantha</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/reflections-of-hal-and-samantha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:57:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/reflections-of-hal-and-samantha/</guid>
      <description>2 channel video installation 6:20 min 2016 A conversation about emotions between the two most iconic operating systems in film history: HAL from “2001: A Space Odyssey” (1968) and Samantha from “Her” (2013).
Stanley Kubrick and Spike Jonze pictured their artificial main characters as voice recognition and speech synthesis operating systems. Unlike the robots in other science fiction movies, HAL and Samantha are conceptualized without the need of a physical body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study on Old Masters</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/studies-on-old-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/studies-on-old-masters/</guid>
      <description>Digital Superimpositions Artistic research on portrait paintings 2012/13 This study on Old Masters is an aesthetic research on portrait paintings by famous artists such as Rembrandt, Rubens and Caravaggio.
For decades, art historians have been discussing whether or not the Old Masters have immortalized themselves in the facial features of their portrayed subjects. To investigate the theory, all known and available paintings containing portraits were merged together. Only self-portraits were excluded from the stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Music Box</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/electronic-music-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/electronic-music-box/</guid>
      <description>Interactive Object 8-bit music device 2015 The “Electronic Music Box” is a wooden hand cranked 8-bit music box, composed of an Arduino, a rotary encoder, 2048 pin headers, 64 LEDs, 8 shift registers, a single 8-ohm speaker, and some electronic parts such as resistors, diodes and switches.
A melody can be physically programmed with simple computing jumpers using a 16×128 pin grid. Every row is dedicated to a freely programmable tone while the columns are holding places for a maximum of 64 notes and pauses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Whispers</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/chinese-whispers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/chinese-whispers/</guid>
      <description>Interactive installation Android app Artisitic research on computational creativity 2016 In this interactive installation, the children’s game “Chinese Whispers” (also known as “telephone”, “gossip”, “operator”, “messenger game”, “Stille Post”) – in which a message is whispered from one person to another – is performed with smartphones using the default speech recognition and speech synthesis software of the device’s operating system.
The often humorous altered last statement in the communication chain is a perfect metaphor for cumulative error caused by feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereotypes</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/stereotypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/stereotypes/</guid>
      <description>Digital Superimpositions 2012 The series of stereotypes consists of various digital superimpositions. Every digital work is the result of 20 to 40 pictures algorithmically merged into a single image.
Similar to Sir Francis Galton’s and technique of Composite Portraiture1 from the 1880s, the digital fusion of images is an experimental approach to examine stereotypical features of the selected input. By repeating similarities of each picture in stack, individual details are getting lost when merged together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die Gedanken sind frei – Thoughts are free</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/die-gedanken-sind-frei-thoughts-are-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/die-gedanken-sind-frei-thoughts-are-free/</guid>
      <description>Digital Superimposition Video loop, 2:30 min 2013 First distributed on leaflets in 1780, the lyrics of the German revolution song “Die Gedanken sind frei” (“Thoughts are free”) are known as a protest for academic freedom and freedom of speech. To this day the song is in the repertoire of student corps and has been used repeatedly over decades to appeal against political oppression.
In this audiovisual projection, a choir performs the protest song in a constant repetition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant QR Camera</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/instant-qr-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/instant-qr-camera/</guid>
      <description>Interactive Object Camera prototype 2015 The “Instant QR Camera” is the first working prototype made out of Polaroid camera, thermal printer, Arduino and smartphone parts. The modified instant camera immediately uploads the captured image and prints the corresponding link as binary code. A smartphone or similar device can decrypt this QR code and download the digital photograph from the cloud.
Submitting to the modern photography culture, the “Instant QR Camera” denies the physical existence of an image, generating the highest level of abstraction that links not only to its digital but also its virtual origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outsourced Film Production</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/outsourced-film-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/outsourced-film-production/</guid>
      <description>Short film 8:30 min 2016/17 What happens when you outsource every single step of a short film production to an online marketplace? What kind of creative piece will be generated out of this labor power if you just give it a budget to work from?
The so called micro-job platforms are mainly offering services online like graphic design works or programming jobs for dumping prices. But you can also order video greetings or ask for creative writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Der Große Zampano – The Great Zampano</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/zampano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/zampano/</guid>
      <description>Installation Kunststück (artistic stunt) by Institut TITHE (Theresa Elster &amp;amp; Tillmann Ohm) 2013 One goldfish. Two bowls. One hoop. Drum roll.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
