<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tillmann Ohm</title>
    <link>https://tillmannohm.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tillmann Ohm</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 19:59:22 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tillmannohm.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>fruit-SALAD</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/fruit-salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 19:59:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/fruit-salad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/fruit-SALAD.png&#34; alt=&#34;fruit-SALAD overview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fruit-SALAD&lt;/strong&gt; is a synthetic image dataset with 10,000 generated images of fruit depictions. This combined semantic category and style benchmark comprises 100 instances each of 10 easily recognizable fruit categories and 10 easy distinguishable styles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The carefully designed Style Aligned Artwork Dataset (SALAD) provides a controlled and balanced platform for the comparative analysis of similarity perception of different computational models. The SALAD framework allows the comparison of how these models perform semantic category and style recognition tasks, going beyond the level of anecdotal knowledge, making them robustly quantifiable and qualitatively interpretable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collection Space Navigator</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/csn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 19:59:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/csn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/CSN-tillmann-ohm.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot CSN&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Collection Space Navigator (CSN) is an explorative visualization tool for researching collections and their multidimensional representations. We designed this tool to better understand multidimensional data, its methods, and semantic qualities through spatial navigation and filtering. CSN can be used with any image collection and can be customized for specific research needs (see Jupyter Notebook or Google Colab).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://collection-space-navigator.github.io/CSN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;🖥️ Online demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://collection-space-navigator.github.io/CSN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;💾 Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://arxiv.org/abs/2305.06809&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;📄 Research paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://collection-space-navigator.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;🌐 Project website&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We introduce the Collection Space Navigator (CSN), a browser-based visualization tool to explore, research, and curate large collections of visual digital artifacts that are associated with multidimensional data, such as vector embeddings or tables of metadata. Media objects such as images are often encoded as numerical vectors, for e.g. based on metadata or using machine learning to embed image information. Yet, while such procedures are widespread for a range of applications, it remains a challenge to explore, analyze, and understand the resulting multidimensional spaces in a more comprehensive manner. Dimensionality reduction techniques such as t-SNE or UMAP often serve to project high-dimensional data into low dimensional visualizations, yet require interpretation themselves as the remaining dimensions are typically abstract. Here, the Collection Space Navigator provides a customizable interface that combines two-dimensional projections with a set of configurable multidimensional filters. As a result, the user is able to view and investigate collections, by zooming and scaling, by transforming between projections, by filtering dimensions via range sliders, and advanced text filters. Insights that are gained during the interaction can be fed back into the original data via ad hoc exports of filtered metadata and projections. This paper comes with a functional showcase demo using a large digitized collection of classical Western art. The Collection Space Navigator is open source. Users can reconfigure the interface to fit their own data and research needs, including projections and filter controls. The CSN is ready to serve a broad community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projection Scans</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/projection-scanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 19:59:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/projection-scanner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/projection-scanner-animation.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Projection Scans gif animation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Projection Scans are interactive in-browser visualizations of different dimensionality reduction techniques, showing 2D, 3D and 6D projections of high-dimensional data. A single, linear dimension or metric provides the possibility to “slice” through the space. This experimental tool tries to better understand the involved methods and to gain intuition of high-dimensional spaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nearest Neighbors Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/nn-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 19:59:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/nn-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/nn-comparison-tillmann-ohm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Semantic Collection Network web application screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Nearest Neighbors Comparisons are in-browser visualizations to better understand the concept of &amp;ldquo;similarity&amp;rdquo; when pre-trained deep learning models such as ResNet50 and VGG19 are used for feature extraction in image analysis. These models are commonly used to measure similarity between images, although their underlying representations are not always easy to interpret. The tool aims to offer means to evaluate the aesthetic similarity between images by comparing different methods and modelsnext to each other. It facilitates the comparison of distance metrics such as cosine similarity and Euclidean distance to perform nearest neighbor searches. With the help of this visualization tool, researchers can gain a visual understanding of the aesthetic similarity of the displayed images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About ARCU&amp;OHM</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/arcu-ohm-logo-tillmann-ohm.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Animated ARCU&amp;amp;OHM logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;human-machine-collaboration&#34;&gt;Human-Machine Collaboration&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;since-2018&#34;&gt;Since 2018&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARCU&amp;amp;OHM is a human-machine collaboration exploring algorithmic curation since 2016. The expert system and »Artificial Curator« ARCU refers to a series of computational projects dealing with the research, selection, and contextualization of artefacts such as artworks, objects, and literature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARCU is continuously developed by artist and researcher Tillmann Ohm as an autonomous research system and algorithmic collaborator for machine-aided exhibition-making, publishing and prototyping curatorial tools for digital collections.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Exhibition Making</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/algorithmic-exhibition-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/algorithmic-exhibition-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/halle14/republic-exhibition-15-tillmann-ohm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Exhibition view KUNST(re_public)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;exhibition--kunstre_public&#34;&gt;Exhibition | KUNST(re_public)&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;halle-14-center-for-contemporary-art-leipzig&#34;&gt;HALLE 14 Center for Contemporary Art Leipzig&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;june-20-to-august-30-2020&#34;&gt;June 20 to August 30, 2020&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://issuu.com/halle14/docs/dokumentation_kunstrepublic_stand_22-4-2021_issuu/38&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&gt; Open exhibition catalog&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARCU&amp;amp;OHM is a curatorial duo consisting of the artist Tillmann Ohm and his »Artificial Curator« ARCU. Based on algorithmic methods and using artificial intelligence, this human-machine collaboration develops experimental curatorial methods and techniques for exhibition programming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this first-of-its-kind, algorithmically-curated art exhibition, the viewer can see works selected from the inventory of purchase awards from the Cultural Foundation of the Free State of Saxony. First, a semantic network was created using the metadata from over 370 works (purchase awards from 2011-2019). The network was then searched for patterns using methods from graph theory. The result was a selection of works related to each other through socio-political topics. The next step of the experiment is to discuss whether this purely data-based curation produced a meaningful exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Le #museeimaginaire</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/museeimaginaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/museeimaginaire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;padding:99% 0 0 0;position:relative;border-style: solid;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/286404759?h=95aca9e02f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%; max-height:800px;background-color:#242424&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;virtual-museum--web-app&#34;&gt;Virtual Museum / Web App&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;computer-vision-selected-instagram-feeds&#34;&gt;Computer vision selected Instagram feeds&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://museeimaginaire.tillmannohm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[ENTER LIVE WORK]&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Livestreams of popular artworks collectively reproduced by social media users.&#xA;A contemporary virtual version of Le Musée Imaginaire – the imaginary museum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each artwork stream channels its latest representations from public Instagram posts based on their physical locations using geotags. Aided by computer vision, every hour Le #museeimaginaire gathers shared auratic moments by museum visitors around the world in nearly real-time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Artist’s Machine</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/artists-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/artists-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/artists-machine-process-tillmann-ohm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Artist&amp;rsquo;s Machine display, book and process figure&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;computer-generated-publication&#34;&gt;Computer-generated publication&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;hardcover-88-pages&#34;&gt;Hardcover, 88 pages&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thesiscommons.org/tj6yf/download&#34;&gt;Download publication as PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Artist’s Machine is a computational research project with the outcome of a publication, generated by an algorithm called &lt;a href=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/arcu/&#34;&gt;ARCU&lt;/a&gt;. From researching topic-relevant literature, detecting semantic structures in hundreds of papers and books, to finally generating a publication with illustrations and paraphrased text citations, every step in the process has been performed automatically – initiated by a simple research phrase that was given as input.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Curator</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/arcu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/arcu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;algorithmic-research-project&#34;&gt;Algorithmic research project&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;since-2016-work-in-progress&#34;&gt;Since 2016 (work in progress)&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARCU (Artificial Curator) is an automated system researching in the thematic field of artificial intelligence in contemporary and future art. ARCU shares relevant news, projects and articles with the world on a daily basis on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/A_R_C_U&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;active&lt;/em&gt;) and on the online blog &amp;ldquo;The Artist’s Machine&amp;rdquo; (&lt;em&gt;discontinued&lt;/em&gt;). Every blog post and tweet by ARCU is generated algorithmically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ARCU maintaines and slowly expands it’s own network of artists and researchers on Twitter to gather and share relevant information about recent articles, artworks, research projects and events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections of HAL and Samantha</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/reflections-of-hal-and-samantha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:57:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/reflections-of-hal-and-samantha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;      &lt;div&#xA;          style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;iframe&#xA;          src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/178727189?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0?dnt=0&#34;&#xA;            style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allow=&#34;fullscreen&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2-channel-video-installation&#34;&gt;2 channel video installation&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;620-min&#34;&gt;6:20 min&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A conversation about emotions between the two most iconic operating systems in film history: HAL from “2001: A Space Odyssey” (1968) and Samantha from “Her” (2013).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stanley Kubrick and Spike Jonze pictured their artificial main characters as voice recognition and speech synthesis operating systems. Unlike the robots in other science fiction movies, HAL and Samantha are conceptualized without the need of a physical body. In both movies, the machine learning process allows the AI to gain consciousness and independence from human input.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Old Masters</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/studies-on-old-masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/studies-on-old-masters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/old-masters-tillmann-ohm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Study on Old Masters process&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;digital-superimpositions&#34;&gt;Digital Superimpositions&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;artistic-research-on-portrait-paintings&#34;&gt;Artistic research on portrait paintings&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;201213&#34;&gt;2012/13&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This study on Old Masters is an aesthetic research on portrait paintings by famous artists such as Rembrandt, Rubens and Caravaggio.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, art historians have been discussing whether or not the Old Masters have immortalized themselves in the facial features of their portrayed subjects. To investigate the theory, all known and available paintings containing portraits were merged together. Only self-portraits were excluded from the stack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Music Box</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/electronic-music-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/electronic-music-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:56% 0 0 0;position:relative;border-style: solid;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/123722801?h=95aca9e02f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%; max-height:800px;background-color:#242424&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;interactive-object&#34;&gt;Interactive Object&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;8-bit-music-device&#34;&gt;8-bit music device&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Electronic Music Box” is a wooden hand cranked 8-bit music box, composed of an Arduino, a rotary encoder, 2048 pin headers, 64 LEDs, 8 shift registers, a single 8-ohm speaker, and some electronic parts such as resistors, diodes and switches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A melody can be physically programmed with simple computing jumpers using a 16×128 pin grid. Every row is dedicated to a freely programmable tone while the columns are holding places for a maximum of 64 notes and pauses. Rotating the hand crank – which is attached to a rotary encoder – activates one column at the time indicated by single LEDs. When a column is activated, the Arduino micro controller checks if a jumper is set and plays the corresponding tone.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Whispers</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/chinese-whispers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/chinese-whispers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;padding:74% 0 0 0;position:relative;border-style: solid;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/162462404?h=95aca9e02f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%; max-height:800px;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;interactive-installation&#34;&gt;Interactive installation&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;android-app&#34;&gt;Android app&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;artisitic-research-on-computational-creativity&#34;&gt;Artisitic research on computational creativity&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this interactive installation, the children’s game “Chinese Whispers” (also known as “telephone”, “gossip”, “operator”, “messenger game”, “Stille Post”) – in which a message is whispered from one person to another – is performed with smartphones using the default speech recognition and speech synthesis software of the device’s operating system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The often humorous altered last statement in the communication chain is a perfect metaphor for cumulative error caused by feedback. While the human brain lacks in recollection of spoken words and tends to complete or correct flawed information creatively, a similar process takes place in the pattern matching event of the speech analysis software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Le #museeimaginaire</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/museeimaginaire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/museeimaginaire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;padding:99% 0 0 0;position:relative;border-style: solid;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/286404759?h=95aca9e02f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%; max-height:800px;background-color:#242424&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;virtual-museum--web-app&#34;&gt;Virtual Museum / Web App&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;computer-vision-selected-instagram-feeds&#34;&gt;Computer vision selected Instagram feeds&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2018&#34;&gt;2018&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://museeimaginaire.tillmannohm.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[ENTER LIVE WORK]&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Livestreams of popular artworks collectively reproduced by social media users.&#xA;A contemporary virtual version of Le Musée Imaginaire – the imaginary museum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each artwork stream channels its latest representations from public Instagram posts based on their physical locations using geotags. Aided by computer vision, every hour Le #museeimaginaire gathers shared auratic moments by museum visitors around the world in nearly real-time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kunstfonds Network</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/kunstfonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 19:59:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/applications/kunstfonds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/halle14/republic-exhibition-14-tillmann-ohm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Semantic Collection Network web application screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kunstfonds.tillmannohm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[ENTER LIVE WORK]&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For the exhibition KUNST(RE_PUBLIC) of HALLE 14 in cooperation with the Art Fund (Kunstfonds) of the Dresden State Art Collections, a curatorial classification as well as algorithmic selection of over 370 works of art from the subsidized purchases of the Cultural Foundation of the Free State of Saxony in the collection was created. The Free State of Saxony promotes the Saxon art scene, among other things, through the annual purchases of works of art, which have taken place since 1992.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kunstfonds Network</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/kunstfonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 19:59:22 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/arcu-ohm/kunstfonds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/halle14/republic-exhibition-14-tillmann-ohm.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Semantic Collection Network web application screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kunstfonds.tillmannohm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;[ENTER LIVE WORK]&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For the exhibition KUNST(RE_PUBLIC) of HALLE 14 in cooperation with the Art Fund (Kunstfonds) of the Dresden State Art Collections, a curatorial classification as well as algorithmic selection of over 370 works of art from the subsidized purchases of the Cultural Foundation of the Free State of Saxony in the collection was created. The Free State of Saxony promotes the Saxon art scene, among other things, through the annual purchases of works of art, which have taken place since 1992.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Die Gedanken sind frei – Thoughts are free</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/die-gedanken-sind-frei-thoughts-are-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/die-gedanken-sind-frei-thoughts-are-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;padding:97% 0 0 0;position:relative;border-style: solid;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/70410749?h=95aca9e02f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%; max-height:800px;background-color:#242424&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;digital-superimposition&#34;&gt;Digital Superimposition&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;video-loop-230-min&#34;&gt;Video loop, 2:30 min&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First distributed on leaflets in 1780, the lyrics of the German revolution song “Die Gedanken sind frei” (“Thoughts are free”) are known as a protest for academic freedom and freedom of speech. To this day the song is in the repertoire of student corps and has been used repeatedly over decades to appeal against political oppression.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instant QR Camera</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/instant-qr-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/instant-qr-camera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tillmannohm.com/img/portfolio/qr-camera-tillmann-ohm.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Instant QR Camera animated gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;interactive-object&#34;&gt;Interactive Object&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;camera-prototype&#34;&gt;Camera prototype&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Instant QR Camera” is the first working prototype made out of Polaroid camera, thermal printer, Arduino and smartphone parts. The modified instant camera immediately uploads the captured image and prints the corresponding link as binary code. A smartphone or similar device can decrypt this QR code and download the digital photograph from the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Submitting to the modern photography culture, the “Instant QR Camera” denies the physical existence of an image, generating the highest level of abstraction that links not only to its digital but also its virtual origin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Der Große Zampano – The Great Zampano</title>
      <link>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/zampano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillmannohm.com/artworks/zampano/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:56% 0 0 0;position:relative;border-style: solid;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/165445812?h=95aca9e02f&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&#34; style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%; max-height:800px;background-color:#242424&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;kunststück-artistic-stunt&#34;&gt;Kunststück (artistic stunt)&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;by-institut-tithe-theresa-elster--tillmann-ohm&#34;&gt;by Institut TITHE (Theresa Elster &amp;amp; Tillmann Ohm)&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One goldfish. Two bowls. One hoop. Drum roll.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
